Hello, my friends, and welcome to exercise number 43.
We are asked to write a function to add a new note after it given not so we have seen before.
How to create the notes, how to create a linkage list and how to link these notes together and how
to create a method that prints the list and how to create a method that push at the beginning.
And you know, this exercise, we need to create a new node.
After a given, this is very important after a given.
So consider that we have these knowns.
One, two three.
This is like this, and we are asked to write in this exercise to add in, you nod here.
Like after two, if I need to create a new node after the node number two, so it would be like this.
I will insert it equal to five.
It was a reference to five and then five reference to three.
So we are adding then node after the second, not OK and we delete this connection.
OK.
So we are going to add then node after the second.
Not.
OK.
After it, given not we give it the name, then number and or index of the second note or any note and
it will insert, then, you know, after it post the video and think about it, how could we do like
this algorithm?
So how to do that, I will create a new method.
It's called insert after so public void, insert after, and we think then not that it is previous,
none that we are going to insert, we we give here and in two perimeters the first one, the pregnant
and the new date, the previous.
Not that we are going to insert in, you know, after it and the date that we are going to insert it
inside the newly inserted no new not OK
insert after this will check one.
If the given note is not not check if they've given.
No is not enough proof, not equal, equal
to null,
null, then go and print system and error message system that out that print and and the given node
given
is not.
OK.
It's very simple and return.
No, we came to that case of everything works fine and the previous not is not not creating the, you
know, how to create it.
It's very simple, as we have seen before, we create new, not equal.
It is like here new underscored and can Walton unplugged and knew that, OK, we have here new date
and not then, you know, we are not inserting, you know, we are inserting a date of Typekit.
OK.
New date.
It's very simple.
Now
here is the trick that we make the next of the new node as next of previous known.
So make next of new known as next.
Previous.
Not new node talk next.
Equal to previous.
Not next.
OK.
You see, guys, how we have break breaking that.
That reference.
And we have switched.
Then, you know, not then make the next of the new node as next of the previous note.
It's very simple.
And here is that trick, OK?
And the fourth step make next.
Of previous node as new.
Not OK.
So previous node took an X equals to new.
Not
OK.
This is how we make the next of the previous node as the new No.
Let's test this example.
We go to the main.
And we have seen here the how to push at the beginning now.
Exercise number forty three
adding the new one on after a given.
Know how to do that link at least the insert after it took two parametres, the preview node and the
end date.
We need to get to insert it after the second.
Not so I will pass second on.
And what are the what is the data that we are going to insert?
As I told you, I am going to insert number five and then data section of the newly created role.
And last thing, I need to print the list.
Let's run and see.
And here we go.
We have four, one, two and five.
We have inserted this.
Not number five correctly.
After the second note, the second note that contains No.
Two.
OK, it's not the second second.
No, but it is because we have inserted for it before it.
But we are going to insert it after this note.
Okay.
So the second note, it's not actually the second shot because it's absurd note because we have inserted
and pushed at beginning.
We have called this method before.
If we if we commend this, we can see that that is on the after the second, not OK.
You see, guys, how we are.
We are advancing our career and advancing our data structure, thinking and our data structure and algorithms
as skills.
It's by simply making and solving like these exercises because they are very important.
We have lectured them in the lectures before, but we need to make them practice.
We have lectured them in C and Java, but we are also making them to anchor the knowledge and going
advanced.
So from these basics, we are going to move to Atlanta.